TRIMAN KAUR

trimankaur1999@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/trimankaur

+91 9878901297

Youtube: @sqliscool Freelance Profile: upwork.com/freelancers/~016c8066517c914b47

Experienced data analyst with over two years of expertise in data analysis within the ecommerce and telecom sectors. Demonstrated success in parsing extensive datasets to extract valuable business insights and uncover fraudulent activities proficiently utilizing Python, SQL, and Quicksight/Power BI.

EDUCATION

University Institute of Engineering and Technology, Panjab University, Chandigarh (2017-2021)

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech) in Computer Science and Engineering

8.93 CGPA

SKILLS

Programming Python, Excel VBA Macros

Visualization Power BI, Quicksight, Jupyter Notebook

Database SQL, Oracle, SparkSQL, Databricks

Tools ETL, Flask, Alteryx, Snowflake

Cloud (AWS) S3, Lambda, Kinesis, Redshift, EMR

EXPERIENCE

May 2022 - PRESENT

Amazon, Bangalore - Data Analyst

- Architected and managed 15+ ETL data pipelines focused on product delivery experiences, leveraging AWS QuickSight
 dashboards. This initiative empowered business decision-making by providing actionable insights to the management,
 resulting in \$2.4B revenue achievement in 2023.
- Automated manual workflows by developing and deploying Python scripts on the cloud. Automated processes included generating structured data dumps using Python Boto3, which were seamlessly stored on Amazon S3. Implemented automated scheduling through CRON jobs for efficient execution.
- Engineered and implemented a comprehensive data architecture for tracking **32** advertising-related metrics across the Amazon Global Selling seller base, facilitated seamless reporting in QuickSight and Excel, operated at a **seller level**, with the capability for **team-based slicing**, providing valuable analytics on a weekly, monthly, and yearly basis

Jan 2021 - April 2022

KPMG GRCS, Gurgaon - Data Analyst

- Developed procedures in **SQL** and **Hadoop** to identify fraudulent **SIMBOX** cases using the Call Detail Records with average monthly fraud value of **3,00,000 ZAR**. Additionally analyzed and identified patterns of the SIM dealers and agents involved in the fraud, and helped the operator blacklist the same.
- Improved the utility of the inventory management solution by developing a **Yolov4** based **custom Machine Learning model** to count the number of objects. To add the utility to the existing solution the model was converted into an **API** using Flask, containerized using Docker and deployed on cloud.
- Prepared various BI dashboards in Power BI for visualizing network audit reports. Automated multiple workflows using
 Python and Pandas thereby reducing the daily work hours from 2 hours to 2 minutes per KPI.

CERTIFICATIONS

Alteryx for Financial Services (Linkedin: 7b002454ad439f70865b7927ae7c93a01e4575be49d66242adfdeefc5f83226a)